<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Crazed Stalkers on Guerilla Showrunner</title>
    <link>http://www.guerillashowrunner.com/tags/crazed-stalkers/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Crazed Stalkers on Guerilla Showrunner</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://www.guerillashowrunner.com/tags/crazed-stalkers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Crazed Stalkers Here!</title>
      <link>http://www.guerillashowrunner.com/2011/01/crazed-stalkers-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 16:54:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.guerillashowrunner.com/2011/01/crazed-stalkers-here/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a happy day. I&amp;rsquo;ve completed the first course from Guerilla Showrunner - Get Crazed Stalkers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And to add on to all that - it&amp;rsquo;s a free course. Completely, totally, utterly and forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one&amp;rsquo;s about your fans. Specifically, it&amp;rsquo;s about the dedicated, hardcore fans (the &amp;ldquo;stalkers&amp;rdquo; - don&amp;rsquo;t worry, I&amp;rsquo;m not actually trying to get you stalked) that every show thrives on, and how to convert your Anonymous YouTube Visitors into people whose first name, kids&amp;rsquo; interests, and credit card numbers you know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The course is in three parts of ten minutes&amp;rsquo; video each (it was going to be five minutes, but it turns out I had rather more stuff to say than I thought I did), in which you&amp;rsquo;ll learn:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;3 things you can do in the next hour to make more of** your casual viewers come back** and get involved in your show.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why your &lt;strong&gt;RSS feed and YouTube subscribers&lt;/strong&gt; aren’t attracting as many viewers as you’d like – and how to fix that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How to design a show or an episode to** fascinate your viewers **- so that whenever they think about your show, they’ll feel good.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why you &lt;strong&gt;don’t need everyone to like your show&lt;/strong&gt; – and how pissing some people off will help turn you into a superstar.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get on the list and recieve the first video, &lt;a href=&#34;http://guerillashowrunner.com/crazed-stalkers-free/&#34;&gt;subscribe to Get Crazed Stalkers.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The link to the first video will drop through your inbox door, if such a thing exists, a few minutes afterward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really hope you guys find this course useful. It&amp;rsquo;s turned into rather a larger project than I had planned - maybe I should have turned it into a paid-for thing instead. Ach, well!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you know anyone who&amp;rsquo;d find a course about getting more and more dedicated fans for their Internet show or whatever else it is they do that gets fans, please do let them know about the course. I really want to help as many people with this stuff as I can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**Permalink for the course: **&lt;a href=&#34;http://guerillashowrunner.com/crazed-stalkers-free/&#34;&gt;http://guerillashowrunner.com/crazed-stalkers-free/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>